Lauren Anthony

Greater Indianapolis, IN – (330) 524-1781 – laurenanthony247@gmail.com laureneanthony.github.io/ linkedin.com/in/lauren-e-anthony/

Career Objective:

I am a Web developer ready to take my career change into tech head on. I thrive when I can learn and explore new things, so what better career than coding which never stops moving and evolving. My prior experience in banking and degrees in music have lent me various valuable skills, which I hope to bring together with my newest skillset and find my niche in the world of technology.

Education:

ELEVEN FIFTY ACADEMY Web Development Bootcamp, Indianapolis, graduated October 2020

24-week part-time immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training.

- Gold Badge: HTML/CSS basics, beginner JavaScript, APIs, DOM, Bootstrap, Git
- Blue Badge: Node, PostgreSql, Sequelize, React
- Red Badge: Typescript, Team Git, Agile, React-Class Components, Material-UI

BALL STATE UNIVERSITY, Muncie, IN

Master of Arts, Concentration: Music, graduated 2018

THE UNIVERSITY OF AKRON, Akron, OH

Bachelor of Arts, Music, and Bachelor of Music, Concentration: Voice Performance, graduated 2012

Technical Skills:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, Node.js, React, PERN application, Heroku deployment, Typescript, Firebase deployment, Database architecture, Front-end & full-stack development, Stateless Components, Session validation, Responsive web design

Technical Projects:

VISION BOARD APP - team project - https://visionboard-app.herokuapp.com/

- Application which provides an aesthetically pleasing, but minimalist canvas in which users can store and organize images, text or
 other items that inspire them. Implements a straightforward user interface that will appeal to both creative professionals and
 everyday users.
- Data Flow diagram which I created: https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/17n-nCOUk8CH-

zSis9PnpDEdk1BkjQmjXbqDADWhNnKc/edit?usp=sharing

MENTAL NOTES THERAPY APP - https://mental-notes-therapy-app.herokuapp.com/

- Application intended for use by individuals with guidance from their mental health provider, which will allow them to keep track
 of important events, insights or behaviors between appointments that can be shared with their provider to better track progress in
 therapy or counseling.
- Full stack application using PostgreSql, Express, React, and Node.
- Server: table implementing full CRUD functionality, session validation with JWT, encrypted passwords.
- Client: written in React, styling with Reactstrap, implemented form validation, connected to 6 endpoints from deployed server.

POKEMON WEATHER API PROJECT - https://lea-poke-weather-api-project.web.app/

Project utilizing 2 open APIs, the Open Weather API & the Pokè API. It fetches displays current weather by location, and
info/stats for your chosen Pokèmon. Utilizes logic to change the weather image icon based on the Open Weather JSON response.

Professional Experience:

FIRST MERCHANTS BANK, Muncie, IN

Lead, Loan Servicing Team September 2019 - Present

- Became the primary resource for team members for questions and assistance on a day to day basis.
- Trained other team members and coordinated cross training efforts within the team.
- Worked on loan maintenance procedures project, including archiving unnecessary procedures, updating procedures which were
 out of date for current practice, and writing procedures for newer processes.

Loan Servicing Specialist March 2019 – September 2019

- Developed daily reporting process to accommodate Freddie Mac Investor Reporting Change Initiative. This was a month's long
 project which included developing the process, testing outcomes, and writing a procedure handbook.
- Learned more advanced maintenance and research to better support the team.

Loan Servicing Associate March 2018 – March 2019

- Completed loan maintenance and transactions including payment posting/corrections, processing code changes, rate changes, payoff processing, fee waivers, and automatic transfer setup.
- · Completed research into loan history and setup and identify the best solution for a customer and implement it.

Service Associate

September 2016 - March 2018

- Built relationships with clients, identified and met their financial needs.
- Completed transactions with friendly and efficient service.
- Worked as part of a team to expand customer base.